Andrey Chasovskikh

Telephone: +436643630284, +79213215519 E-mail: <u>andrey.chasovskikh@gmail.com</u>

Website: http://andreycha.info
Location: Vienna, Austria

Profile

I'm a software developer with more than 8 years of experience in the field developing multitier enterprise applications. My experience includes development of financial software, ETL solutions, and medical information systems. I have experience in both frontend and backend applications, with a bias to backend development. I have an extensive knowledge of .NET platform and C#, plus some experience using Java. Fond of clean code. Able to write and understand asynchronous and multithreaded code. I'm also used to working in agile environment.

Professional experience

bwin (part of GVC Holdings PLC), Vienna, Austria. May 2016 - present time

Position: senior software engineer

• Developing backend services with the focus on performance and availability

Keywords: C#, .NET, T-SQL, Apache Kafka, MS Visual Studio, Redis, MS SQL Server, IIS, git, SVN, GitLab, VersionOne, NUnit, Moq, Kanban

Broadridge Financial Solutions (Paladyne Systems before Sept. 2011), St. Petersburg, Russia. March 2011 – April 2016

Position: software developer/senior software developer

- Took part in developing greenfield product for reference data quality and arbitration:
 - integrated with Security Master product: loading and keeping up-to-date 10+ mln entities
 - developed a number of input and output adapters for data transformation engine, made a lot of improvements based on a real usage
 - implemented apply/diff algorithm for document storage
 - bugfixing and adding various features across the application
- Took part in developing and supporting Security Master, a product for managing securities reference
 data. This included estimating, designing and developing features (from UI to backend code and
 database), supporting existing functionality, writing tests (mostly employing TDD) and technical
 documentation, code review, solving client issues. Developed major features for a number of
 releases:
 - designed and developed 'Custom Dictionaries' feature
 - helped to keep a client by developing custom FormPF solution
 - took part in developing 'Auto-Failover' feature
 - took part in high-level design of 'Custom Calculated Fields' feature, developed it from scratch
 - bugfixing and adding various features across the application
- Was helping Price Master team for several months:
 - investigated and fixed several major performance issues, both backend and UI
 - streamlined build and deployment processes
- Was replacing the sole developer of a product for loading reference data from vendors into other products, ETL Manager, which is written in Java. Mentored two new developers for 6 months.

Keywords: C#, .NET, Java, Powershell, T-SQL, Infragistics, DevExpress, MS Visual Studio, IntelliJ Idea, MS SQL Server, IIS, Tomcat, TFS, git, Jira, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, TDD, MS Test, xUnit, JUnit, RhinoMock, Moq, NSubstitute, Mockito, Scrum, Kanban

BrainSystems, St. Petersburg, Russia. September 2010 - March 2011

Position: software developer

- Helped to get a client by developing e-archive system prototype: full application design and development.
- Took part in developing Java web application for medical municipal institution, both front-end and backend parts.

Keywords: C#, .NET, Silverlight, Entity Framework, WCF RIA Services, MS SQL Server, Java, Smart GWT, Oracle, Jasper Reports, JBoss, NetBeans, SVN, Redmine

Kostasoft, St. Petersburg, Russia. September 2008 – September 2010

Position: junior software developer/software developer

- Took part in developing and supporting medical information system, Avicenna.NET. This included writing new functionality (from UI to backend code), supporting existing codebase and writing technical documentation.
- Streamlined development process by introducing weekly sprints and product backlog.
- Improved knowledge sharing across the team by leading weekly retrospective meetings.

Keywords: C#, .NET, T-SQL, DevExpress, MS Visual Studio, MS SQL Server, SVN, Gemini

Academic experience

St. Petersburg Polytechnical University. February 2010 – February 2014

Have lead exercises and several lectures for "Databases" course (MS SQL Server, T-SQL) every spring semester.

Education

2010 - 2012, St. Petersburg Polytechnical University

Faculty of Engineering Cybernetics, Information and Control Systems department. Postgraduate student (unfinished).

2004 - 2010, St. Petersburg Polytechnical University

Faculty of Engineering Cybernetics, Information and Control Systems department. Specialist degree in Software Engineering. GPA: 4.5/5.0.

Talks & publications

- "async/await: avoiding common mistakes", .NEXT Moscow, December 2014
- "Windows Phone applications security", HackInParis, June 2013
- "Inspection of Windows Phone applications", BlackHat Abu Dhabi, December 2012
- "Clustering algorithms overview", http://web-analitik.info/, September 2010

Certificates & diplomas

- 3rd prize at "VK.com messenger for Windows Phone" contest (2012)
- MCTS: Windows Application Development with Microsoft .NET Framework 4 (2011)
- Brainbench C# 3.0 Fundamentals Master (2011)
- Microsoft IT Case Cup semifinalist diploma (2011)
- Exigen Services' ".NET Workshop", letter of archievement (2009)